Guide to the Ulysses Kay papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Music by Kay, 1939-1991
  - Suite for Strings, 1947
    - Miniature scores, 1961 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Concerto for Orchestra, 1948
    - Sketches and notes, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      (includes notes concerning composing for film)
  - Portrait Suite, 1948
    - Sketches, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      (includes sketch for ending of Suite from "The Quiet One", 1948)
    - Full sketch, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Excerpt from holograph of full score, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Full score, circa 1952 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - The Quiet One, 1948
    - Holograph, circa 1948-1952 (Box 46)
    - Full score, circa 1948-1952 (Box 47)
  - Suite from "The Quiet One", 1948
    - Sketch for ending, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      (included among sketches for Portrait Suite, 1948)
  - Quintet for Piano and Strings, 1949
    - Full score, circa 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Full score, circa 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Set of string parts, circa 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Solemn Prelude, 1949
    - Set of parts, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Score and set of parts, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 81)
      (later edition)
  - String Quartet No. 1, 1949
    (originally String Quartet in F)
    - Holograph of score, circa 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Holographs of parts, circa 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Score, circa 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Score, circa 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      (facsimile; title changed)
    - Score, circa 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Set of parts, circa 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Set of parts, circa 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - A Madrigal, 1949
    (became second song of Two Dunbar Lyrics, 1965)
    - Score and copy of new text by Kay, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
      (facsimile score: new text added by Kay and song retitled In Summer Hours; copy of text contains markings)
  - Sinfonia in E, 1950
    - Sketches, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      (includes sketch for "Little Suite for Band" [Short Suite, 1950])
    - Miniature score, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      (contains markings; includes note originally inserted inside score)
    - Miniature score, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Song of Ahab, 1950
    - Draft of text, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Sketch of vocal part with notes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Full sketch, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Sketch of piano reduction, circa 1950 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Holograph of full score, circa 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Holographs of baritone solo and orchestral parts, circa 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Holograph of piano reduction, circa 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Solo baritone part, circa 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Orchestral parts, circa 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Full score, circa 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Full score, circa 1950-1953 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Full score, circa 1953 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pietà, 1950
    - First sketch, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Full sketch, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Full sketch of piano reduction, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Full score, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Full score, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Piano reduction with separate English horn part, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Piano reduction with separate English horn part, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Short Suite, 1950
    - Sketch, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      (included among sketches for Sinfonia in E, 1950)
    - Full score, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Full scores, 1957 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Set of parts, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Set of parts, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Fugitive Songs, 1950
    - Holograph of vocal part, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Full score, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Full score, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - On the Cowboy Trail, 1950
    - Correspondence, preliminary sketch, and full sketch, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      (correspondence from Miriam Friedman, dedicatee)
  - Two Meditations, 1950
    (originally Two Voluntaries)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Full sketch, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Holograph, circa 1950 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Score, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Copy of score with orphaned cover from published score, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Brass Quartet, 1950
    - First sketch, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Holograph of full score, circa 1950-1952 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Holographs of parts, circa 1950-1952 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Sets of parts, 1958 (2 items) (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Miniature scores, 1958 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The Lion, the Griffin and the Kangaroo, 1951
    - Preliminary sketches and full sketch, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 20)
      (full sketch mistitled "The Lion, the Griffin and the Unicorn")
  - Three Pieces After Blake, 1952
    (see also Triptych on Texts of Blake, 1962)
    - Full score, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Piano reduction, circa 1953 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Piano reduction, circa 1953 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Vocal score, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      (also score for Triptych on Texts of Blake, 1962, inscribed to Irene Oliver by the composer)
    - Vocal score, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      (also score for Triptych on Texts of Blake, 1962)
  - A Lincoln Letter, 1953
    - Full score, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Choir scores, 1958 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Triumvirate, 1953
    - Holograph, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Full score, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Choir score, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Serenade for Orchestra, 1953-1954
    - Page from sketch of second movement, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Holograph, circa 1954-1958 (Box 48)
    - Full score, circa 1954-1958 (Box 49)
      (facsimile; incomplete: begins with page 3)
    - Study score, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - How Stands the Glass Around?, 1954
    - Choir scores, 1956 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - What's in a Name?, 1954
    - Choir score, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - A Wreath for Waits, 1954
    - Choir scores, 1956 (4 items) (Box 1, Folder 37)
      (each song published separately; includes two copies of "Noel")
  - Six Dances for String Orchestra, 1954
    - Sets of parts with full score, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 85)
      (both sets contained within the same Folder; full score contains markings)
  - The Boor, 1954-1955
    - Libretto with correspondence, 1955 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      (correspondence to librettist Vladimir Ussachevsky)
    - Carbon-copy of libretto, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Libretto, 1955 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Note, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Piano reduction, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Piano reduction, circa 1961 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Full score, undated (Box 50)
  - A New Song: Three Psalms for Chorus, 1955
    - Full score, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Choir scores, 1961 (3 items) (Box 1, Folder 42)
      (each song published separately; contain markings)
    - Choir score of "Sing Unto the Lord", 1961 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Choir scores, 1961 (3 items) (Box 1, Folder 44)
      (each song published separately)
  - Grace to You, and Peace, 1955
    - Full sketch, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Notes, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Choir scores, 1957 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Second String Quartet, 1956
    - Full score, circa 1957 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Set of parts, circa 1957 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The Juggler of Our Lady, 1956
    - Early version of libretto, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - First revision of libretto, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Copy of first revision of libretto, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
      ("10-17-61" written in pencil on cover page)
    - Second revision of libretto, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Final libretto, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - First sketch, notes, and other sketches, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      (some sketches written on the reverses of parts for The Quiet One, 1948)
    - Full sketch, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Kay's outline of opera, circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Notes and "Sequential Analysis", circa 1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      (found inside piano reduction)
    - Notes, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Holograph cast and instrument list, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
      (contains sketch of stage)
    - Draft of page for holograph of full score, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Full score, undated (Box 51)
    - Memo to orchestra members from Ward Woodbury, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      (found inside full score)
    - Piano reduction, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Ten Short Essays, 1957
    (revision of Thirteen Pieces for Children, 1940, originally Ten Pieces for Children)
    - Holograph, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Score, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Score, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Score, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Serenade No. 2, 1957
    - Holograph of full score, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Holographs of parts, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Two Short Pieces, 1957
    - Holograph, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Scores, 1962 (2 items) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Two Hymns, 1957
    - Transparent score, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - FDR: From Third Term to Pearl Harbor, 1958
    - Outline of film, circa 1958 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Full sketch, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Holograph, 1958 (Box 52)
    - Full score, 1958 (Box 53)
  - Organ Suite No. 1, 1958
    - Score, circa 1959 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Score, circa 1959 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Score, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Russo-Finnish War, 1958
    - Outline of film, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Notes, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - City of Magic, 1958-1959
    (holographs arranged as found (divided by orchestra))
    - Ideological Outline, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 6a)
    - Shot list, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Outline of main and end title sequences with correspondence, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      (correspondence from producer Frank Rosa, Jr.; outline contains markings)
    - Full sketch, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Notes, circa 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - List of sound effects, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Holographs of cues for "A" orchestra (large), 1958-1959 (Box 54)
    - Holographs of cues for "B" orchestra (small), 1958-1959 (Box 55)
  - Submarine, 1959
    - Contract, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Outline of program, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Full sketch, 1959 (Box 15)
    - List of music cues with timings, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Notes, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Holograph, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Full score, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Phoebus, Arise, 1958-1959
    ("Tears, Flow No More" and "The Epicure" rearranged and published separately; see below)
    - Draft of text, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Final version of text, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Full sketch, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Sketch of piano reduction, circa 1959 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Notes, circa 1958 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Holograph of piano part, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
      (incomplete?)
    - Set of piano reduction scores, undated (7 items) (Box 16, Folder 5)
      (contains markings; Folder also contains title page in Kay's hand used as wrapper)
    - Piano reduction for "Epilogue", undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Incomplete set of piano reduction scores, undated (5 items) (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Incomplete full score, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
      (facsimile; contains markings; includes nos. 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6)
  - Tears, Flow No More, 1959
    (arrangement from Phoebus, Arise, 1958-1959)
    - Choir scores, 1965 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - The Epicure, 1959
    - Choir scores, 1965 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Incidental Music to "Scene and Song", 1959
    - Holographs of full score and piano reduction, 1959 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - The Fall of China, 1959
    (episode from the television series The Twentieth Century; see below)
    - Outline of episode, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Full sketch, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Holograph, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Full score, 1959 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Twentieth Century, 1959
    (see also The Fall of China, 1959)
    - Sketches for "main title" and "end titles", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Holograph of "main title", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Holograph of "end title", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Score of "main title", 1959 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Scores for five versions of "end title", 1959 (5 items) (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Quality, 1959
    - Storyboard, circa 1959 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Full sketch, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Holograph, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Full score, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Quality Cue A, 1959
    (see also Quality Cue B, 1959)
    - Storyboard, circa 1959 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Sketches, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      (includes additional page of notes)
    - Holograph, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Full score, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Full score, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      (facsimile; contains markings; includes makeshift wrapper signed by composer)
    - Full scores, 1959 (2 items) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Quality Cue B, 1959
    (see also Quality Cue A, 1959)
    - Copy and storyboard, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      (contain markings)
    - Sketches, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Holograph, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Full score, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Full score, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Full scores, 1959 (2 items) (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Hymn - Anthem on the Tune "Hanover", 1959
    - Holograph, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Choir scores, 1960 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - The Shape of Things, 1960
    - Outline of program with correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 62)
      (contain markings; correspondence from producer Lane Slate)
    - Screenplay, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      (contains markings; includes envelope with notes on reverse)
    - Sketches, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Full score for beginning of cue 5, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper advertisement, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      (The New York Times, January 22)
  - Serenade No. 3, 1960
    - Holograph, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Printing masters for parts, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Set of parts, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - AMF, 1960
    (television commercials for American Machine and Foundry: "Hands" and "Leisure")
    - Storyboard for "Hands", 1960 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Versions of storyboard for "Leisure", 1960 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Full sketch, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Holograph, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - The Three Musketeers, 1960
    - Sketch, circa 1960 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Full sketch, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Notes, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Holograph and note, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      (holograph ordered as found: follows order outlined on enclosed note)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Excerpts from full score, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      (facsimile; includes scores for cues 2, 4, and 5)
    - Production schedule, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Newspaper advertisement, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 68)
      (The New York Times, December 1)
  - Admiral Byrd, 1960
    - Screenplay, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Outline of episode, circa 1960 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Full sketch, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Notes, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Holograph, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      (incomplete: missing cut 18)
    - Full score of cut 18, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Full score, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      (facsimile; includes additional copies of cuts 2 and 6; contains markings)
  - Swiss Watches¸1961
    - Storyboard, circa 1961 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Full sketch, circa 1961 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      (sketch dated 1960 but composition dated 1961 in diary)
    - Holograph score, circa 1961 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Holographs of parts, circa 1961 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      (contain additional markings)
    - Full scores, circa 1961 (2 items) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Trigon, 1961
    - Full score, 1961 (Box 56)
  - String Quartet No. 3, 1960-1961
    - Sketch, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      (contained among sketches for Ivory Snow, 1964)
    - Full score, circa 1962 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Set of parts, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Set of parts, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
      (incomplete: missing cello part; contains markings)
  - Flowers in the Valley, 1961
    - Choir score, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Choir scores, 1962 (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - To Light That Shines, 1962
    - Holograph, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Land, 1962
    - Full sketch, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Holograph, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Notes and documents, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Full score, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      (facsimile; includes additional copy of cue A; contains markings)
  - Forever Free: A Lincoln Chronicle, 1962
    - Preliminary sketches, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Full sketch, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Full score, circa 1962 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      (facsimile; contains markings; see correspondence found inside score)
    - Full score, circa 1962 (Box 57)
    - Set of parts, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 86)
      (score contains markings)
    - Set of parts, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Full score, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Nosotros, 1962
    - Screenplay, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Sketch, circa 1962 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Full sketch, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Holograph, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      (pages 21-27 function also as pages 39-45)
    - Full score, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Full score, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Choral Triptych, 1962
    - Full score, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Going Home, 1962
    (working title: "Baluba Film")
    - Outline script, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Notes and outline of music, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 75)
      (outline contains markings)
    - Sketches, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Holograph, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Full score, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Full score, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Theme, 1962
    - Full sketch, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Holograph, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      (included among sketches for second of Two Impromptus for Piano, 1986 contains additional markings)
  - Triptych on Texts of Blake, 1962
    (reduction of Three Pieces After Blake, 1952)
    - Copies of text, undated (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Full score, circa 1962 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      (facsimile; identity hidden with tape; contains markings)
    - Violin and cello parts, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Vocal score, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      (also score for Three Pieces After Blake, 1952, inscribed to Irene Oliver by the composer)
    - Vocal score, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      (also score for Three Pieces After Blake, 1952)
  - Inscriptions from Whitman, 1963
    - Sketch, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      (included among sketches for Fantasy Variations, 1963)
    - Full score, 1963 (Box 58)
    - Piano reduction, circa 1963 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Piano reduction, circa 1963 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Fantasy Variations, 1963
    - Preliminary notes and sketches, 1958-1961 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      (includes sketch for Inscriptions from Whitman, 1963)
    - Sketch of variation 2, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Full score, undated (Box 59)
    - Miniature score, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Miniature score, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Umbrian Scene, 1963
    - Sketches and outline, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      (one sketch a partial facsimile)
    - Full score, circa 1963 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Full score, circa 1963 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Full score, circa 1963 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Miniature score, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      (contains marking on page 13)
    - Miniature score, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      (contains marking on page 25)
  - Theme, 1963
    - Sketch, circa 1963 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Holograph and photocopy of different holograph, circa 1963 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Ivory Snow, 1964
    - Versions of storyboard, 1963 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Holograph of version for two pianos and sketches for chamber version, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      (includes sketch for String Quartet No. 3, 1961)
  - Crest - Exploratory, 1964
    - Script, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Sketch, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Holograph of score, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      (contains additionally markings)
    - Holographs of parts, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Emily Dickinson Set
    - Choir score, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Choir scores, 1965 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Essay on Death, 1964
    - Shooting script, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Program sequence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Negative photographs of outline for sound and music, 1964 (2 items) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Sketches, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Full sketch, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Notes, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Holograph and note, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Concert Sketches, 1964-1965 (see Prologue and Parade, 1977)
    - Sketches, 1964-1965 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Full score, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Presidential Suite, 1965
    - Early note and sketch, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Full sketch of piano reduction, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 12)
      (page 7 is written on reverse of page 5)
    - Full score, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Full score, undated (Box 60)
    - Note, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Program note, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - The Game, 1963-1965
    (see also Two Excerpts from "The Game", 1965)
    - Synopsis, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Libretto, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      (contains markings; includes correspondence from librettist Judith Dvorkin)
    - Libretto, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Libretto revisions, circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Formal outline, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Preliminary sketches, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Full sketch of Act I, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Holograph of piano reduction for Act I, circa 1965 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Scores of piano reduction for Act I, circa 1965 (2 items) (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Score of piano reduction for Act I, circa 1965 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Score of piano reduction for Act I, circa 1965 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Score of piano reduction for Act I, circa 1965 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Two Excerpts from "The Game", 1965
    (see The Game, 1965)
    - Partial sketch of second excerpt, circa 1965 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Holograph of second excerpt, circa 1965 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Negative copy of score, circa 1965 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Scores, circa 1965 (3 items) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Two Dunbar Lyrics, 1965
    (see A Madrigal, 1949)
    - Text, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Early holograph of choir score for "A Starry Night", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Early holograph of full score for "A Starry Night", undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Holograph choir score, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Holograph full score, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Choir score, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Full score, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Full score, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Choir score, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - A Thing of Beauty, 1966
    - Screenplay, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Preliminary sketch, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Full sketch, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Two Songs for Children, 1966